[
    {
      "question": "1. What does HTML stand for?",
      "options": ["Hyper Text Markup Language",
                "Home Tool Markup Language",
                "Hyperlinks and Text Markup Language",
                "Hypertext Markup Language"],
      "answer": "Hyper Text Markup Language"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. Which technology is primarily responsible for the styling of web pages?",
      "options": ["HTML", "JavaSript", "CSS", "Python"],
      "answer": "CSS"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. What does CSS stand for?",
      "options": ["Creative Style Sheet", "Computer Style Sheet", "Custom Style Sheet", "Cascading Style Sheet"],
      "answer": "Cascading Style Sheet"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Which programming language is mainly used for adding interactivity to websites?",
      "options": ["HTML", "Python", "JavaScript", "CSS"],
      "answer": "JavaScript"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. What is the purpose of a front-end web development framework like React or Angular?",
      "options": [
        "To manage databases and server-side logic",
        "To create a visually appealing user interface",
        "To handle serve-side routing",
        "To interact with web servers"
      ],
      "answer": "To create a visually appealing user interface"
    },

    {
      "question": "6. Which part of web development is responsible for handling data storage and retrieval?",
      "options": ["Front-end development", "Back-end development", "Full-stack development", "Middleware development"],
      "answer": "Back-end development"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. What is the primary function of a web server in the context of web development?",
      "options": [
        "Rendering web pages on the clients browser",
        "Executing JavaScript code",
        "Storing user data",
        "Handling HTTP requests and serving web pages"
      ],
      "answer": "Handling HTTP requests and serving web pages"
    },
    {
      "question": "8.Which of the following is the Web Application equivalent to querySelectorAll?",
      "options": [
        "#",
        "&",
        "!",
        "$"
      ],
      "answer": "#"
    },
    {
      "question": "9.When does javascript code appear in inline within an HTML file",
      "options": [
        "between or outside the 'script' tag",
        "Between the header tag",
        "Outside the 'script' tag",
        "Between the 'script' tag"
      ],
      "answer": "Between the 'script' tag"
    },
    {
      "question": "10.Which of the following is not a back-end programming language commonly used in web development?",
      "options": [
        "PHP",
        "Ruby",
        "Java",
        "HTML"
      ],
      "answer": "HTML"
    }
  ]